How about we use that? Combine that with number three. Do not use arable land. Because crops are already growing on that land that's very scarce around the world. Number two: Don't compete with food crops. That's already a well established entity, they don't need another entry. And lastly the most precious resource we have on this Earth is fresh water. Don't use fresh water. If 97.5 percent of the world's water is saltwater, 2.5 percent is fresh water. Less than a half percent of that is accessible for human use. But 60 percent of the population lives within that one percent. So, combating my problem was, now I have to be extreme green and meet the big three. Ladies and gentlemen, welcome to the GreenLab Research Facility. This is a facility dedicated to the next generation of aviation fuels using halophytes. A halophyte is a salt-tolerating plant. Most plants don't like salt, but halophytes tolerate salt. We also are using weeds and we are also using algae. The good thing about our lab is, we've had 3,600 visitors in the last two years. Why do you think that's so? Because we are on to something special. So, in the lower you see the GreenLab obviously, and on the right hand side you'll see algae. If you are into the business of the next generation of aviation fuels, algae is a viable option, there's a lot of funding right now, and we have an algae to fuels program. There's two types of algae growing. One is a closed photobioreactor that you see here, and what you see on the other side is our species — we are currently using a species called Scenedesmus dimorphus. Our job at NASA is to take the experimental and computational and make a better mixing for the closed photobioreactors. Now the problems with closed photobioreactors are: They are quite expensive, they are automated, and it's very difficult to get them in large scale. So on large scale what do they use? We use open pond systems. Now, around the world they are growing algae, with this racetrack design that you see here. Looks like an oval with a paddle wheel and mixes really well, but when it gets around the last turn, which I call turn four — it's stagnant. We actually have a solution for that. In the GreenLab in our open pond system we use something that happens in nature: waves. We actually use wave technology on our open pond systems. We have 95 percent mixing and our lipid content is higher than a closed photobioreactor system, which we think is significant. There is a drawback to algae, however: It's very expensive. Is there a way to produce algae inexpensively? And the answer is: yes. We do the same thing we do with halophytes, and that is: climatic adaptation. In our GreenLab we have six primary ecosystems that range from freshwater all the way to saltwater. What we do: We take a potential species, we start at freshwater, we add a little bit more salt, when the second tank here will be the same ecosystem as Brazil — right next to the sugar cane fields you can have our plants — the next tank represents Africa, the next tank represents Arizona, the next tank represents Florida, and the next tank represents California or the open ocean. What we are trying to do is to come up with a single species that can survive anywhere in the world, where there's barren desert. We are being very successful so far. Now, here's one of the problems. If you are a farmer, you need five things to be successful: You need seeds, you need soil, you need water and you need sun, and the last thing that you need is fertilizer. Most people use chemical fertilizers. But guess what? We do not use chemical fertilizer. Wait a second! I just saw lots of greenery in your GreenLab. You have to use fertilizer. Believe it or not, in our analysis of our saltwater ecosystems 80 percent of what we need are in these tanks themselves. The 20 percent that's missing is nitrogen and phosphorous. We have a natural solution: fish. No we don't cut up the fish and put them in there. Fish waste is what we use. As a matter of fact we use freshwater mollies, that we've used our climatic adaptation technique from freshwater all the way to seawater. Freshwater mollies: cheap, they love to make babies, and they love to go to the bathroom. And the more they go to the bathroom, the more fertilizer we get, the better off we are, believe it or not. It should be noted that we use sand as our soil, regular beach sand. Fossilized coral. So a lot of people ask me, "How did you get started?" Well, we got started in what we call the indoor biofuels lab. It's a seedling lab. We have 26 different species of halophytes, and five are winners. What we do here is — actually it should be called a death lab, 'cause we try to kill the seedlings, make them rough — and then we come to the GreenLab. What you see in the lower corner is a wastewater treatment plant experiment that we are growing, a macro-algae that I'll talk about in a minute. And lastly, it's me actually working in the lab to prove to you I do work, I don't just talk about what I do. Here's the plant species. Salicornia virginica. It's a wonderful plant. I love that plant. Everywhere we go we see it. It's all over the place, from Maine all the way to California. We love that plant. Second is Salicornia bigelovii. Very difficult to get around the world. It is the highest lipid content that we have, but it has a shortcoming: It's short. Now you take europaea, which is the largest or the tallest plant that we have. And what we are trying to do with natural selection or adaptive biology — combine all three to make a high-growth, high-lipid plant. Next, when a hurricane decimated the Delaware Bay — soybean fields gone — we came up with an idea: Can you have a plant that has a land reclamation positive in Delaware? And the answer is yes. It's called seashore mallow. Kosteletzkya virginica — say that five times fast if you can. This is a 100 percent usable plant. The seeds: biofuels. The rest: cattle feed. It's there for 10 years; it's working very well. Now we get to Chaetomorpha. This is a macro-algae that loves excess nutrients. If you are in the aquarium industry you know we use it to clean up dirty tanks. This species is so significant to us. The properties are very close to plastic.
¿Qué tal si la usamos? Combinamos eso con el número 3, no usar tierra cultivable. Porque esas tierras ya se están cultivando y son escasas en el mundo. Nº 2: No competir con cultivos alimentarios. Eso está ya bien establecido. no se requiere nada más. Por último, el recurso más precioso que tenemos en la Tierra es el agua dulce; no usar agua dulce. Si el 97.5% del agua en el mundo es salada, 2.5% es agua dulce. Menos de la mitad de esto está disponible para uso humano. El 60% de la población se abastece de ese 1%. Para resolver mi problema, tenía que ser verde extremo y cumplir con esas 3 grandes medidas. Damas y caballeros: bienvenidos al laborartorio de investigación GreenLab. Este es una entidad dedicada a la próxima generación de combustibles de aviación que usan halófitas. Una halófita es una planta que tolera la sal. A la mayoría de las plantas no les gusta la sal, pero las halófitas la toleran. También usamos malezas, al igual que algas. Lo bueno de nuestro laboratorio es que hemos tenido 3600 visitantes en los últimos 2 años. ¿A qué se debe eso? Es porque estamos haciendo algo especial. En la parte baja ven al GreenLab, obviamente. A la derecha ven las algas. Estando involucrados en la próxima generación de combustibles de aviación, las algas son una opción viable. Hoy hay mucho financiamiento y tenemos un programa de algas para combustibles. Existen dos maneras de desarrollar algas. Una es un fotobiorreactor cerrado que ven aquí. Lo que aparece al otro lado es nuestra especie, la que usamos en el momento que se llama Scenedesmus Diamorphis. Nuestro trabajo en la NASA es tomar los datos experimentales y computacionales para hacer la mejor mezcla para el fotobiorreactor cerrado. El problema con estos fotobiorreactores es que son bastante costosos, están automatizados, lo que hace muy difícil producirlos a gran escala. ¿Qué se usa a gran escala? Se usan sistemas de tanques abiertos. En todas partes del mundo se están cultivando algas con como circuitos, como ven aquí. Como un óvalo con una rueda de paletas para mezclar bien pero cuando llega a la última ronda, que yo llamo la cuarta, se estanca. Tenemos solución para eso. En el sistema de estanque abierto de GreenLab usamos algo que ocurre en la naturaleza; las olas. Con la tecnología de olas, en el sistema de tanques abiertos, logramos mezclas del 95% y el contenido de lípidos es mayor al del sistema del fotobiorreactor cerrado, lo cual, pensamos, es significativo. Pero las algas tienen una desventaja; son muy costosas. ¿Habrá alguna forma de producir algas económicamente? La respuesta es, sí. Hacemos lo mismo que con las halófitas, es decir, adaptación climática. En GreenLab tenemos seis ecosistemas primarios que van alterándose desde agua dulce hasta llegar a la salada. ¿Qué hacemos? Tomamos una especie potencial, empezamos con agua dulce, le agregamos un poco de sal. Éste, el segundo tanque aquí, equivale al ecosistema de Brasil. Al lado de los campos de caña de azúcar se pueden tener nuestras plantas. El siguiente tanque representa África, el siguiente Arizona, el siguiente Florida, y el que sigue representa California o el mar abierto. Lo que estamos intentando es conseguir una sola especie que pueda sobrevivir en cualquier parte del mundo, aunque sea un desierto árido. Hasta ahora hemos tenido mucho éxito. Ahora, uno de nuestros problemas. Para los agricultores hay 5 requisitos para tener éxito: Se necesitan semillas, suelo, agua, sol y, por último, fertilizantes. La mayoría usa fertilizantes químicos. Pero ¿saben algo? Nosotros no usamos fertilizantes químicos. ¡Un momento! Veo mucho verde en tu laboratorio. Seguro usan fertilizantes. Aunque no lo crean, en los análisis de los ecosistemas de agua salada, el 80% de lo que necesitamos está dentro de estos tanques. El 20% faltante es nitrógeno y fósforo. Nuestra solución natural es, peces. No picamos los peces para echarlos ahí. (Risas) Usamos los deshechos de los peces; es más usamos peces poecilia de agua dulce con la técnica de adaptación climática gradualmente desde agua dulce hasta agua salada. Los poecilias de agua dulce son baratos, les encanta tener bebés y les fascina ir al baño. Cuanto más van al baño, más fertilizante obtenemos, mejor para nosotros, aunque no lo crean. Cabe notar que usamos arena como piso, arena común de playa, o sea, crustáceos fosilizados. Muchos me preguntan, ¿cómo empezaste? Bueno, empezamos con lo que llamamos biocombustibles de laboratorio bajo techo. Es un laboratorio semillero donde tenemos 26 especies diferentes de halófitas y cinco son ganadoras. Lo que hacemos es... debería llamarse laboratorio de la muerte, porque intentamos matar semillas, hacerlas resistentes y luego vamos al laboratorio verde. Lo que ven en la esquina inferior es una planta experimental de tratamiento de residuos donde estamos desarrollando, una macroalga de la que hablaré en un minuto. Y por último, ese soy yo en el laboratorio para mostrarles que también trabajo; no solo hablo de lo que hago. Aquí están las especies de plantas, Salicornia virginica. Es una planta maravillosa, me encanta. Se ve por todas partes, desde Maine, por todas partes hasta California. La adoro. La segunda es Salicornia Bigelovi, muy díficil de encontrar. Es la que tiene más alto contenido de lípidos, pero con una desventaja: es enana. Y ahora, la Salicornia europaea, la más grande o más alta. Lo que estamos intentando con selección natural o biología adaptativa, es combinar las tres y hacer una planta más alta con mucho lípido. Cuando un huracán diezmó la Bahía de Delaware, los campos de soya desaparecieron. Se nos ocurrió una idea: ¿podremos tener una planta con la que se pueda recuperar el suelo de Delaware? La respuesta es sí. Y se llama malva de la costa, Kosteletzkya virginica, repitan eso cinco veces, bien rápido, si pueden. Es una planta 100% útil; las semillas como biocombustible y el resto para forraje. Ha estado ahí por 10 años y funciona muy bien. Ahora veamos la Chaetomorpha, que es una macroalga a la que le encantan los nutrientes en exceso. saben que se usa para limpiar tanques sucios. Esta especie es muy importante para nosotros. Sus propiedades se acercan al plástico.
We are trying right now to convert this macro-algae into a bioplastic. If we are successful, we will revolutionize the plastics industry. So, we have a seed to fuel program. We have to do something with this biomass that we have. And so we do G.C. extraction, lipid optimization, so on and so forth, because our goal really is to come up with the next generation of aviation fuels, aviation specifics, so on and so forth. So far we talked about water and fuel, but along the way we found out something interesting about Salicornia:
Intentamos ahora convertir estas macroalgas en bioplástico. Si tenemos éxito, revolucionaremos la industria de los plásticos. Tenemos ya una semilla para el programa de biocombustibles. Tenemos que hacer algo con esta biomasa que resulta. Hacemos extracción GC, optimización de lípido y demás, porque nuestra meta es crear la próxima generación de combustibles para aviación... y lo que sigue. Hasta ahora hemos hablado de agua y combustibles, pero en el camino nos encontramos con algo interesante sobre la Salicornia;
It's a food product. So we talk about ideas worth spreading, right? How about this: In sub-Saharan Africa, next to the sea, saltwater, barren desert, how about we take that plant, plant it, half use for food, half use for fuel. We can make that happen, inexpensively. You can see there's a greenhouse in Germany that sells it as a health food product. This is harvested, and in the middle here is a shrimp dish, and it's being pickled. So I have to tell you a joke. Salicornia is known as sea beans, saltwater asparagus and pickle weed. So we are pickling pickle weed in the middle. Oh, I thought it was funny. (Laughter) And at the bottom is seaman's mustard. It does make sense, this is a logical snack. You have mustard, you are a seaman, you see the halophyte, you mix it together, it's a great snack with some crackers. And last, garlic with Salicornia, which is what I like. So, water, fuel and food. None of this is possible without the GreenLab team. Just like the Miami Heat has the big three, we have the big three at NASA GRC. That's myself, professor Bob Hendricks, our fearless leader, and Dr. Arnon Chait. The backbone of the GreenLab is students. Over the last two years we've had 35 different students from around the world working at GreenLab. As a matter fact my division chief says a lot, "You have a green university." I say, "I'm okay with that, 'cause we are nurturing the next generation of extreme green thinkers, which is significant." So, in first summary I presented to you what we think is a global solution for food, fuel and water. There's something missing to be complete. Clearly we use electricity. We have a solution for you — We're using clean energy sources here. So, we have two wind turbines connected to the GreenLab, we have four or five more hopefully coming soon. We are also using something that is quite interesting — there is a solar array field at NASA's Glenn Research Center, hasn't been used for 15 years. Along with some of my electrical engineering colleagues, we realized that they are still viable, so we are refurbishing them right now. In about 30 days or so they'll be connected to the GreenLab. And the reason why you see red, red and yellow, is a lot of people think NASA employees don't work on Saturday — This is a picture taken on Saturday. There are no cars around, but you see my truck in yellow. I work on Saturday. (Laughter) This is a proof to you that I'm working. 'Cause we do what it takes to get the job done, most people know that. Here's a concept with this: We are using the GreenLab for a micro-grid test bed for the smart grid concept in Ohio. We have the ability to do that, and I think it's going to work. So, GreenLab Research Facility. A self-sustainable renewable energy ecosystem was presented today. We really, really hope this concept catches on worldwide. We think we have a solution for food, water, fuel and now energy. Complete. It's extreme green, it's sustainable, alternative and renewable and it meets the big three at GRC: Don't use arable land, don't compete with food crops, and most of all, don't use fresh water. So I get a lot of questions about, "What are you doing in that lab?" And I usually say, "None of your business, that's what I'm doing in the lab." (Laughter) And believe it or not, my number one goal for working on this project is I want to help save the world.
es un producto alimenticio. Hablamos de ideas que vale la pena difundir ¿no? Qué tal esta: en África subsahariana, próxima al mar, agua salada, desierto árido... ¿qué tal si cultivamos esa planta; la mitad como alimento y la mitad como combustible. Podemos lograrlo sin grandes costos. Hay un invernadero en Alemania que lo vende como alimento saludable. Se cultiva y aquí en el medio, hay camarones para encurtir. Tengo que contarles un chiste. A la Salicornia se le conoce como frijoles de mar, espárragos marinos y algas en escabeche. Estamos encurtiendo algas en escabeche, en el medio. Bueno, pensé que era divertido. (Risas) Y abajo, mostaza náutica. y tienes un gran platillo con galletas. Y por último, ajo con Salicornia, que es lo que más me gusta. O sea, agua, combustible y alimentos. Nada de esto sería posible sin el equipo del GreenLab. Así como Miami Heat tiene sus 3 grandes, nosotros tenemos nuestros 3 grandes en GRC de la NASA: Ahí estamos con el profesor Bob Herndricks, nuestro temerario líder, y el doctor Arnon Chait. La columna vertebral del GreenLab son los estudiantes. En los últimos 2 años, hemos tenido 35 estudiantes de todo el mundo, trabajando en el GreenLab. A propósito, mi jefe de división repite: "tienes una universidad verde". Y yo le digo: "Me parece bien porque estamos formando la próxima generación de pensadores en verde extremo, lo que es importante". Resumiendo, primero les presenté lo que pensamos es una solución global para alimentos, combustibles y agua. Algo falta para completarlo. Obviamente usamos electricidad. Les tengo una solución;; usamos fuentes de energía limpia. Tenemos dos turbinas eólicas conectadas al GreenLab y esperamos que pronto lleguen unas 4 o 5 más. También estamos usando algo bastante interesante... Hay un campo de paneles solares en el Centro de Investigación Glenn de la NASA, sin uso desde hace 15 años. Junto con algunos colegas, ingenieros eléctricos, vimos que eran viable, así que los estamos restaurando. En unos 30 días los conectaremos al GreenLab. Y la razón por la que ven rojo, rojo y amarillo, es que mucha gente piensa que los empleados de la NASA no trabajan los sábados. Esta es una foto tomada en sábado. No hay autos pero vean mi camioneta amarilla. Yo sí trabajo los sábados. (Risas) Así muestro que estoy trabajando. Porque hacemos lo necesario para lograr el trabajo; todos lo saben. Hay un concepto relacionado con esto: Usamos el GreenLab como base de prueba para la idea de una microred inteligente en Ohio. Tenemos la capacidad de hacerlo y creo que funcionará. Allá en el laboratorio de investigación de GreenLab. Un ecosistema de energía renovable autosostenible, es lo que he presentado hoy. En verdad espero y deseo que este concepto se extienda por todo el mundo. Creemos tener una solución para alimentos, agua, combustibles, y también energía. Todo completo Es verde extremo, sostenible, alternativo y renovable, y cumple con las tres grandes de GRC: no usa tierras fértiles, no compite con cultivos alimenticios, y sobre todo, no usa agua dulce. Me preguntan mucho, "¿y tú qué haces en el laboratorio?" Mi respuesta habitual es, "No te importa. Eso es lo que hago". (Risas) Aunque no lo crean, mi primera meta de trabajo en este proyecto es: quiero ayudar a salvar el mundo.